The reality is like anthropic and open
AI they're playing a whole different
game that no one will compare from a
model perspective to where they are
especially when you think on the open
source side. I think the investors maybe
industry everyone keeps waiting for some
crack in the armor. The reality is is
that what's going on guys? Today we've
got a very special treat. We have Dan
Ies the legend himself here in the
studio. He is now the partner and senior
managing director at Yorkville Ives.
It's a brand new merchant bank that he's
building. And he spills the tea on every
single thing that you care about in the
AI trade. We talk about the Chinese open
source models. What's going on with
anthropics revenue slowing down? Where
are the big bottlenecks? What does he
think about these companies that have
seen their stock appreciate so much? How
is he thinking about politics and all
the regulation, the data center
moratorum in New York City, and so much
more? All of that covered in this
conversation with Dan Ies. All right,
Dan. The AI bears have all kinds of new
things that they're worried about. Let's
start with the Chinese openweight open-
source models. Now all of a sudden
everyone thinks that they're going to
take out the big model labs. What's your
take?
>> Look, it's a it's a mini deepseek moment
in terms of the the fears, but I mean
you've talked about this. The reality is
like anthropic and open AI, they're
playing a whole different game. No one
will compare from a model perspective to
where they are, especially when you
think on the open source side. I think
the investors maybe industry everyone
keeps waiting for some crack in the
armor. The reality is is that the models
will get cheaper over time and there's
going to be 5 10x more models over the
next few years. The value will be in the
data and the moat and that continues to
ultimately be I think that's the game
that anthropic and open AI are playing.
That's why they're so focused on the
enterprise. That's the right move.
models and carps talked about it will
become more and more commodities but for
the first time in 30 years it's not even
a question the US is ahead of China when
it comes to tech and I think that's just
such an important point where we are now
what's interesting to me is uh they're
complaining that there's been this like
distillation attack and that the Chinese
models are essentially drifting or
drifting off of you know these big
American companies but there's a lot of
people in America like wait a minute uh
I think Anthropic just signed a $ 1.5
billion settlement with, you know,
500,000 authors for for taking the
books. Uh there's a lot of people
complaining about didn't you kind of
just like do a distillation attack off
of the the IP to be able to train the
model originally.
>> Yeah. People in glass houses shouldn't
throw stones, right? And I think just
the reality is the models are built off
content. I think when it comes from a
model perspective, what China's doing,
it's smart because look, they also have
like one hand tie behind their back.
They don't have Nvidia chips,
>> but even if you do, you have a called a
third rate Nvidia chip. I mean, you have
Huawei, you have some, you know,
obviously some competition there, but
the models need to get smarter and
smarter. And I think what you've seen
with the Gemini delay, look, Gemini's
come, you know, they've fallen back a
bit, but I think that's why it speaks to
the pressure, capbacks, raising capital.
This arms race, it is not slowing down.
It's third inning. Mhm. What's I also
find pretty interesting about uh this
entire competition is that we basically
have American closed source models and
then we have Chinese open source
openweight, you know, type models. I
don't hear a lot of conversation about
American open- source, but I know that
Jensen seems pretty allin on American
open source being a big option. Well, I
think the issue if you go back to what
Zuckerberg and Meta with Llama, I mean
Llama call that like a shot at that from
like an open-source perspective, you
know, that was one way I think they
realized like back to the drawing board.
>> I think Nvidia and Jensen their view is
okay, we'll do an open source model. We
don't because that's not their game.
Like their game is like we'll create one
that's fine because it's better for the
industry. It goes back to like more open
source, more people using it, models are
cheaper. Look, the biggest issue when it
comes to anthropic and open AI, a lot of
it just comes down and over time the
prices will get cheaper. It's the cost
>> because cost is the inhibitor relative
to AI adoption. So when you look at
models getting cheaper, see I'll take
like the other side of it. I don't view
it as a negative. I view more
competition would drive prices down
which would drive adoption down. So I
think that that's the broader view. Like
if you're a bull in this market, AI
revolution, chips, data center, you need
the models to get cheaper. When we go
and we look at uh Grock and uh Meta,
both of them in their latest releases of
models or iterations, the leading thing
they were putting forward was the cost.
That is very different than OpenAI and
Anthropic. They've been talking about
performance mostly. Is this now kind of
like your margins my opportunity and
these guys are just looking for an angle
to be able to catch up or do you think
that the entire industry now is going to
shift from it's all about performance to
it's about efficiency and and cost is
this big component?
>> I think you're going to have the good
yard or whatever you want to call it the
open anthropics they're going to be like
they're not lowering prices
>> there will be others that will come if
it you go in pocket books like yeah we
have a great it's going to be cheaper
wallets. So when you look at Grock and
when you look what Meta has done that's
sort of been their game. Gro the thing
is a lot of it just comes down to
content but it speaks to broader SpaceX
Tesla the what really Musk is
essentially building price will be it's
going to be a differentiator it's going
to open doors but then it comes down to
like if you're an enterprise today what
are you looking I mean you you're you're
essentially chat GPT or quad and quad
has become pervasively probably the best
model in the world
>> yeah what I also find interesting
interesting that we don't yet quite
understand and we're going through this
actively with the the Sylvia product
that we're building is congrats on that
we're dealing with finance and so you
want the model to have capitalistic you
know uh tendencies and and answers and
so this idea of like cultural weights if
we were to go put an open source Chinese
model to answer questions do they have
socialist type ideas or you know kind of
eastern world views that are baked in
that they may not even be explicit they
they may be somewhat but you know kind
of uh uh lightly and implicitly put in
which then starts to change the answers
and influence behavior. It's been a big
concern with Tik Tok and you know many
other kind of feed or algorithm driven
things. What's your take there?
>> It's going to be bifurcated. It's almost
two sort of worlds that will play side
by side together. The models the
cross-pollination between a Chinese
model and ultimately US model and ch
you're going to sort of have that
cordoned off. There are social issues.
There's capitalistic. There's worries
about government relative to on a data
perspective. It's US and China today,
but like as Middle East, as eventually
Europe, as rest of world, this is just
it's the beginning of what we're going
to see as models. Cuz I could argue like
2 3 years from now, you go to Malaysia,
Malay, they might have like their own
country. They might have it specifically
to finance and industrials and others.
So I think you are going to see that
across the board which is why the models
are so important as you start to see
this fourth industrial revolution the
use cases I mean you've seen front and
center with what you're doing on the
consumer side on enterprise all these
data centers that are getting built it's
like a stadium you got to fill with
people you got to fill it ultimately
with GPU with capacity and with use
cases
>> you know what I find interesting is um
it seems like the AI industry could
learn something from the crypto industry
which usually you know, those two groups
are have been some separate but there
used to be this thing called the fat
protocol thesis in crypto and the entire
idea was that all value was going to
acrue to the protocol layer whether that
was you know bitcoin ethereum whatever
obviously that's not what happened
instead you got applications and then
you got infrastructure you got the
protocol etc it seems like AI is going
through the same thing and I haven't
heard anyone explicitly say it's like
the fat AI model thesis but that's
pretty much what people who are betting
like the models are going to eat the
whole stack I just don't see that world
happening like I see it being very much
fractured and I think that's good
because it ultimately uh creates a
better performance, better uh
applications and lower cost for the
customer.
>> I think that you know we went through a
period and I think some of that was
maybe like the PR problem that AI
created but it was a view like anthropic
eating everyone's lunch. I mean even go
back to like cyber security the view
like AI was going to you know in terms
of anthropic was going to eat cyber
security. The reality of cyber security
is going to be I'd say it's going to
budget's going to double over the coming
years because of AI. If you look from a
the SAS apocalypse, there will be
software companies disintermediated as
we see. But I agree with you is that I
think right now I think the biggest
misconception or I think maybe the way
that the market is maybe you know
misjudging how this is all going to play
out underestimating the scale and scope
and the second third fourth derivatives
of what's playing out today. Today is it
a small number of players that are that
are the winners? Yeah. But this is it's
building the Las Vegas. It's like we're
in Vegas 1955 building the strip. That's
essentially what we're doing. So every
one of these companies knows on the
hypers scale like we need our spot on
the strip. If we don't do that now
others will come in. Now you could be
like why are you spending so much money
now? Goes back to the whole capbacks you
know debate. They know this is year
three of an 8 to 10 year cycle and you
could argue a 20 to 30 to 40ear cycle
when it comes to physical AI. That's
right now this sort of tugof-war that
we're seeing in this market. Today's
episode is brought to you by Figure. If
you're into Bitcoin, you already know
selling's the last thing you want to do.
But at the same time, life [music]
happens, man. Opportunities arise, bills
come up, and markets move. That's where
Figure comes in. Instead of selling your
Bitcoin, figure let you borrow against
it so you can get cash without losing
your position and may also avoid
triggering a tax event. Right now, their
loans are around 8.91% interest. That's
9.9% [music] APR at a 50% loan to value.
So, you keep your upside but still get
liquidity. And I know the first question
people ask is, "Yeah, but is it safe?"
It's a good question. Figure uses MPC
custody, which basically means your
Bitcoin stays in its own segregated
[music] wallet. It's not being lent out,
pulled, or sitting on some exchange.
They also have optional liquidation
protection, which helps if [music] the
market gets volatile. And if you're on
the other side, like you've got cash and
you want yield, they've got something
called Democratized Prime. It's earning
up to 9% APY, [music] paid hourly, and
is backed by real world assets, not just
token inflation. [music] So whether
you're trying to hold your Bitcoin
longterm or actually put capital to
work, it's a pretty interesting setup.
If you want to check it out, I've got a
link in the description that you can go
to or you can go to figurearkets.co/p.
>> You know, the other thing I find uh
pretty fascinating is there's these big
bets on specialized workflows versus
general purpose models. And you know,
with Sylvia, we're making this massive
bet on specialized workflows. But as
we've built that product, what we
realized is like the model is very
important. Um, but it's a lot of the
proprietary technology you're building
around it. It's, you know, aentic file
systems, it's memory, it's, you know,
even maybe like model routing is a
pretty interesting idea.
>> So, uh, Sierra, Brett Taylor's, uh,
company, um, he's been talking about, I
think they have an engineering blog
that's out where they have something
like 20 different models. And so, for
those that that don't understand how
this works is when you ask a query on
Chat GBT, they're routing it to some
model that that you've chosen on on
their platform. But if you're using
Sierra or Sylvia or any of these other
platforms, that query may be best
answered by Claude or by, you know, Chat
GBT or uh Kimmy K3 or whatever. And so
that model router is basically taking
the query and putting it to the right
model. Now, when I see that, what it
starts to tell me is actually the world
is not going to have general purpose.
It's going to start getting super
specialized and then the model router is
going to be the general purpose, you
know, type technology. Is that the way
you see this? That's been our whole
thesis. Like our whole thesis is
there's a view like AI is just a takes
away jobs. Everyone's going to just use
these to get rid of whatever white
collar workforce, whatever you want.
It's wrong. I'm not saying there's not
disruption. The reality is is that each
you're going to see specific you they
could be using the same model, but
there's going to be so many
specifications and so many different
mousetraps that they build. That's
what's going to separate you from him or
her, whatever it may be. And I think the
reality is is that that's more and more
what companies are realizing.
The proprietary data workflow and what
I'll call the model enhancements or
maybe algorithms that are specific to
companies, whether it's financials,
industrial, manufactur, go back to
manufacturing. You take company A and B,
they're using the same model. The
reality is what's the differentiation?
if they're using the same model, it's
going to be the proprietary nature of
it. And what that's going to do, it's
going to create more companies, but it
goes back to like it is an innovation
boom that's happening in this country.
And I just think it's something where
we're going to look back years from now
and be like, "Wow, that was just the be
I didn't realize that A, B, and C was
going to happen." I think that that's
what makes it such an exciting time. But
it's also the tugof-war that we see
between capbacks and monetization.
>> Well, I think now people have seen this
chart of like the mag 7, you know, uh,
free cash flow is basically just fallen
off a cliff. I mean, it almost look like
cartoon. At the same time, the
semiconductor, you know, revenues have
just exploded the opposite direction and
we're literally taking money from the
Mag 7 and we're just shoving it into all
the semi uh, companies. Is that
sustainable? Do you worry about, you
know, Mag 7 type companies doing this or
or what's your take? Look, my view is
like they're making
10year, 20-year bets.
>> Now, grant they've had to take out
little debt, do some equity raises,
offbend some others. Yeah. But they
recognize, see, the difference is the
reason capbacks is not getting
ultimately cut or you're not seeing
hesitation. as they talk to more of
their enterprises, more of their
companies, they realize what the
pipeline is going to look like. Now, of
course, Oracle being like maybe like the
poster child for this like took on more
and more debt. Stock obviously got
crushed because OpenAI 300 billion call
another 300 billion of deals. So, like
where is the breaking point where
companies need to ultimately peel back?
I just think it's one where we are
talking about an 18 to 24month period
that will ultimately set the stage for
the next decade. And that's what that's
what these companies are doing. And look
investors some will say I'm done. No mas
patient. I don't want to see this free
cash. I want to see them pull back. But
it comes back to like 2022.
Jensen, why are you spending on AI?
You're you're a gaming GPU company. Like
go back to like 2008 financial crisis.
Apple, you released the iPhone. It was
great in 2007. Now with the financial
crisis, why would you continue to double
down here? Everyone has Blackberries.
Let's just focus back on your core.
Nadella, why go after cloud? You're not
a cloud company. Just focus on Noia and
the traditional Microsoft. Like I'm just
saying you could go back to decades and
there were companies they went through
gut check periods. That's what the
industry is going through right now. And
basically what you're arguing is uh
they're making these bets. And I guess
if you just extrapolate this out, if
they're right, they're not investing
enough.
>> If they're wrong, then it almost isn't
going to matter how much they invested
because they're they're blowing the
money. But then to that point, if they
were wrong, by this point in the cycle,
they would have already saw, you know,
wherever the smoke come out of the
chimney, whatever the signs are like,
whoa, come, they're not seeing the ROI,
they're not. But I could tell you like
pal I could tell you like whether it's
Palunteer whether it's snowflake whether
it's what we see on cyber security
private companies data bricks data you
see it more and more that the companies
they're seeing the ROI
>> that's why they're spending more whether
it's insurance financials biotech
pharmaceuticals is AI ultimately going
to be like the first true discovery to
get rid of a Parkinson's a cancer and
Alzheimer's like I'm just trying to walk
through like I There's a view today
where it's just okay, it's going to take
away my job and increase my electricity
bill and that's a huge PR problem
created by the industry. The benefits of
this are just starting to to be realized
and I think that look that speaks to the
market like that's why every earning
season is so important validation what
demand but I can just tell you from
recent Asia trip like it's still what 12
to1 demand and supply when it comes to
chips. When you think of those
bottlenecks, right? You go on these
trips, you go and you visit the
manufacturers. I think memory chips like
we can go through all these different
components. Where do you see the
bottlenecks that are not getting solved?
>> Memory is the biggest bottleneck because
there's no all like a Pal Ives memory
data that we're going to build in New
York or New. You're talking about like
on one hand the amount of memory
players. That's why from SK you know to
to Micron to everything we see you know
across Korea and you've seen in the
Cosby like there memory is the biggest
constraint that we see and you probably
don't have equilibrium till 2028 2029
now you could argue different on in
terms of the stocks what are they
reflecting is it cyclical has this
almost changed the cyclicality power is
clearly the biggest constraint and I
think biggest constraint is just data
centers need to get built in the US for
this all to happen. That's there there's
no gray
as we go into like midterm elections and
like political grandstanding and no data
centers here and that whether it goes
from like you know if there was a a
mortorium in New York and then it goes
down Tennessee or Texas I think the
biggest risk relative to US China it's a
data center B because there's no debate
where we're winning on chips models
hyperscalers IP China winning on
robotics and energy. But if data centers
are not built here, that's that would be
like, you know, a hospital not having,
you know, surgeons or not having, you
know, the technology to do what they do.
So that that continues to really be the
bottlenecks.
>> What do you think about Hokll's uh
moratorium in New York? I think it's so
dangerous because the problem is like
and like me and you, we go to DC a lot,
you know, and like there's some
politicians that I've met with whether
they're senators or they get it. They're
technologists. They understand not just
the job creation, but what this
ultimately mean in terms of ripple
effect. When you get into the political
grandstanding argument about it,
especially with a lot of politicians
that are still using Blackberries, the
problem is is that it's dangerous
because that's the limiting factor. Now,
I get some of the risks and some of the
concerns, you know, whether it's a, you
know, water, cooling, sound, and other
things that need to ultim obviously get
vetted. That's the danger because
ultimately it's those jobs. They go to
other states. That's why right now like
I spend more time going to Texas to see
companies than a lot of times Silicon
Valley. I'm just saying in terms like
the shifts and I just think that it's
very dangerous when the political piece
gets in the technology piece because it
comes down to like for the first time in
30 years like I said US is ahead of
China when it comes to we don't want to
cut ourselves off at the knees. Mhm.
Now, it it feels like some of this is
driven by local communities, but some of
it is being driven by lobbyists and, you
know, kind of the big machine. Um, it is
always fascinating to me that people who
are yelling and screaming about climate
change and then they're screaming about
the next thing and now it's data
centers.
>> But when you go and you look at the
data,
>> they bring down property taxes in the
most concentrated data center locations.
Uh, the job creation, not just in the
data center. Yes. There's not a ton of
different
>> restaurants con you get this huge thing
obviously the construction industry
explodes when you get this stuff
happening but I I think the part that
maybe people get the least understanding
of is then you also like the latency
that you get the advantage you get by
putting the data center locally ends up
having this ripple effect throughout
every single business that's there
>> and then companies move there. Mhm.
>> See, it's also it's the ri go down to
Austin, go within 40 miles of Austin in
any direction because it's the ripple
effect of companies that ultimately move
there and then build businesses there
around data centers. You're going to
have a lot of parts specifically like in
the Midwest where there were companies
and I've seen like my whole career,
right? Like just going so much around
the world around this country where
there were cities that had a factory
where there was GM Ford, whatever it may
be. Then all of a sudden got closed.
Okay, that got shipped to Mexico, China,
Malaysia, wherever it may be. You the
town, so many people lost their jobs.
Went from 70,000 people to 15,000.
Education, so many other issues that
have happened. Now all of a sudden
there's opportunities where those could
actually come back and get built. And
I'm just saying like this is a
renaissance. it is a boom in this
country and that's probably the thing
that like I'm most sensitive to where I
get people could have different
political views or whatever but when it
comes to this it gets dangerous when it
becomes a political game relative to the
reality of I think what it's ultimately
going to be well the the politics of
this too I think is um you have on one
hand uh it seems like the big model labs
are basically begging the government to
go and ban any sort of Chinese open
source models etc. Then you've got local
communities that are basically begging
the government to do moratoriums or ban
data centers. Like I don't know. It kind
of seems like all the people who were
supposed to be in the free market,
everyone's turning to the government and
saying play referee. Well, I think look
part of the problem the industry created
a huge PR problem. I'm saying self if
you tell everyone almost like pull the
ladder up on there. It's like this is
going to wipe out jobs. It's going to be
the crusher. We're going to own
everything. They were bragging. No, but
you don't have to be Stephen Hawkins to
figure out that's going to be a huge
issue. Now you maybe have seen a
curtailing there because also the
reality from a job perspective. Yeah, I
could tell you speaking so many
universities every year like it is a
huge fear. But if people think that AI
only means them not getting a job or
losing their job and their electricity
bill going higher and is only just a few
companies that are successful because of
it, I get it. Like yeah, it's like a
ground swell. So I think that's the
first thing that needs to happen. You
need to separate the reality from the
Fed talks about no technology last 100
years ever been a net job detractor. But
it all comes down to like that's some of
the it's some of the the battles that
you're going through right now and it's
it's a dangerous time relative to like
if we shoot ourselves in the foot for
because for the first time now we are in
pole position.
>> Mhm. When you think about these
companies like uh Alphabet etc.
obviously their uh earnings when these
things start to come out. I think that
people are evaluating them as okay,
Alphabet's making big AI bets, but they
have search and they have YouTube and
they have you know other things. When
you go and look at memory companies
maybe as an example you could use you
know SK uh bit look at Micron all these
different companies
>> their stocks again look like cartoons
like they just have exploded vertical.
>> When you're talking to clients and and
folks like
>> should they be allocating, should they
not? How do you think about, you know,
there's a shortage, but the stock's up
at, you know, 1,200%.
>> I think part of it was like as someone
like myself, I spend so much time like
in Korea for years. Korea was almost
like a forgotten market.
>> Mhm.
>> But yet the memory was all there. That's
why now like New York City cab driver
talks about the Cosby,
but no one even knew what the Cosby was
in terms like you know a typical person
a few years ago. I think it's it's
probably it's gotten like like a swing.
It's probably gotten overdone on one
side, you know, maybe not appreciated on
the other relative to hyperscalers
versus memory. The reality is like the
memory players,
they will continue to be massively
successful because of the hypers scour,
but you can't just forget about the ones
that ultimately will be probably the
biggest winners in the whole thing in
terms of big tech. Cuz remember without
a lot of times there's a view mag 7's
not important anymore. It's
idiosyncratic. It's really more memory
and chips that you have to focus on
relative to broader tech. I disagree
because when you think about the endgame
here, the ones that will benefit the
most are the hypers scalers versus just
the when you start to segment it to like
the memory or other players on the chip
side.
>> Mhm. And I guess as you go further and
further through the stack, are there
other places that maybe people are not
talking about yet, but you think will be
big bottlenecks?
>> Look, I just think the biggest
bottleneck in this country is energy. I
don't even think there's a debate then
we can say we talk about the data center
buildout but I think energy continues to
be the biggest debate because look we
need
3 to 4x more energy to ultimately if we
went to 20 25% of companies fully
embracing AI in terms like stat you need
3 to 4x more energy now where that's
coming is it pipeline
you know is it
Is it NASA gas? No, I'm saying is it
like Yeah. I mean, you know, obviously
you talk about space, but it's like
nuclear,
>> you know, and then you start to go to
like fision, nuclear fusion. I think
that right now is the biggest question
because we have the technology but at
one point you you hit you hit an energy
shortage and I think that's something
where that right now there's a race
going on that probably look that doesn't
happen for another call 2 3 years but
that that will be like a big part of
this buildout when it comes to the
energy and the infrastructure build out
in terms of what's happened in this
country.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by Tik
Tok for business. If you run a company
you are probably already spending a
bunch of money on ads, search X, maybe
Meta, but there's a platform your
competitors are sleeping on and the
window to move first is closing. Tik Tok
has over 200 million monthly active
users in the US alone and 51% of that
reach is unique, meaning that those
users aren't reachable on any other
major platform where you are already
buying. Unlike follower-based platforms,
Tik Tok's algorithm rewards strong
creative, not audience size. That means
a well-made video from a brand no one's
heard of can reach millions of relevant
users. For companies trying to acquire
users cost- effectively, that's a
fundamentally different model. Tik Tok
for business gives you fullfunnel tools
built for performance. Whether you're
looking to drive awareness, introduce
your products, or convert new audiences,
Tik Tok is becoming an important
discovery engine for businesses and
cryptocurrency alike. If you're a
founder, a CMO, or growth lead and you
haven't run a Tik Tok campaign yet,
now's the time to change that. Click on
the link in the description or go to
Anthony Pompiano.splash
that.com. Again, click on the link in
the description and go check out Tik Tok
for business today. Today's episode is
brought to you by Arch Public. Arch
Public has just expanded its agentic
trading platform, Beyond Crypto. So, pay
attention. This is a big one. Now, they
are automating strategies across stocks,
commodities, and ETFs. And I think that
this is going to be huge. You can now
automatically take profits when one
market hits new all-time highs and
rotate that capital into other markets,
showing more opportunity. Whether you're
rotating capital into AI stocks, gold,
if you're investing in the S&P 500, or
you're accumulating Bitcoin, Arch Public
brings real discipline and automation to
your investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Arch Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to
archpubic.com
right now. Connect with their team. Set
up a time. Bring your accountant if
you'd like. Then you can learn what
automated trading can do for you.
archpub.com.
It was just reported that Anthropic's
revenue is still growing, but it has
significantly slowed from the growth
rate that it had previously. Does that
worry you?
>> It just but it's it's ultimately healthy
over time because it speaks like just
like you said more models, more
competition,
pricing will get driven down. You can't
just have one company owning the market.
Open AI, they're obviously going to
continue accelerate. You're seeing
people picked off left and right in
terms of, you know, the the tech talent
and I think it just shows like this
industry is more than just anthropic and
open AI. It is it's spreading and you're
see look go back to like Caterpillar or
you could argue on the defense side like
where Lohee Martin could be when it
comes to defense tech relative to AI.
as almost like a third fourth
derivative. And I think investors now
are starting to I think better
appreciate the scope of what this is all
going to do.
>> Mhm.
>> When you think about your kind of
position in the market, you've made a
big jump. You're going to go and you and
Yorkville are coming together to create
uh kind of a brand new modern merchant
bank. Explain what this is.
>> Yeah. And look for me, you know, over 25
years in the street, like I wanted to
try to build something. I mean, look,
you've built so much stuff, you know, in
terms of, you know, successfully and
obviously it's unbelievable for me. It's
like I've never built anything. And I I
really saw the opportunity the last few
years in terms of a true merchant bank
one where it's an investment bank, but
you actually could skin the game. you
actually have the capital to also invest
in the companies, you know, as it's
obviously siloed off and to create an
endto-end
bank that I think there's a huge gap in
the market. Yorkville and those I've
known personally and professionally for
decades
>> and for me relative to like the fourth
industrial revolution and where we are
and the amount of capital that's going
to be needed and so many small midcap
companies that are yelling from the
mountain tops, you know, no one's really
paying attention to them. I think that's
the opportunity that we see and why I'm
just so excited to be building this is
really a modern merchant bank.
>> And when you think about that merchant
bank, what you guys will do uh
investment banking services, you have
research and then you also make
investments in uh certain deals as well.
>> Exactly. And that's and I think that's
now if you go back like the Thomas
Wisle, Robbie Stevens, you Allen coming
like you go back to the early days of
what Hangard did at Jeff. I mean there
there are obviously like a lot of
examples of it. Goldman early days. I
just feel like relative to where the
market is, there's a huge opportunity
like to do with the right people, right?
It's something in the right industries,
you know, relative to tech, energy,
infrastructure, you know, potentially
healthcare. And that's why I'm so
excited. And for me, it's like I knew
like this was the time. It was like
right time, right place, right partner
for Yorkville lives like to really do
something where I feel like we'll have
like like anything you'll have skeptics
that you but I feel like something that
we could really disrupt Wall Street and
when you are successful what does that
look like? Is it that uh it's the number
one merchant bank? Is it specifically
focused on just AI? How do you kind of
look at what the north star is? I mean
for me the north star is companies when
they're looking to like whether like
they want like phenomenal research
whether they want a company thing from
birth to you know like you know from the
beginning from a private company into a
public company as a trusted partner
investors to look at us as like the
experts right when it comes to AI tech
energy infrastructure are we going to
have like you know hundreds of people no
But we're going to be like SWAT team
like we're going to be someone as a firm
where like we're going to have
phenomenal people, great culture,
entrepreneurial and ones where like when
companies are looking for a partner,
when investors are looking for a
partner, they look at us and for someone
like me that's done it for decades, for
York that's done it for decades, we just
feel like it's just like a unique
combination that just makes us so
excited.
>> I agree. I definitely agree with that.
Um, what are your predictions for the
next 6 months or so? through, you know,
through the end of the year when it
comes to uh kind of the big AI trade.
>> Yeah, I think we're going we're going to
continue to go through these like gut
check moments, whether it's a Chinese
models, whether it's capex debate, no
moss, you know, investors are, you know,
sort of putting the sort of white flag,
they want companies to ultimately cut it
instead of see
free cash on monetization.
But I just think it all comes down to
like the monetization bets will start to
show in the second half of the year
>> and is that shows whether it's on the
hypers scalers whether it's in software
whether it's really across the the stack
that to me is the key to this market.
Now, of course, it's like Fed, oil,
gold, crypto, you know, you you go
through like so, but it's tech that will
ultimately drive this market or if the
market obviously gets hit, it's tech
that is the bedrock. So, I just think
that we're going into like it's still
third inning
>> of the AI revolution. You could argue is
it second, is it fourth, but those that
say it's seventh, eighth, you haven't
it's Vegas 1955. You're just building
the strip. And I think that's also why
the debate relative to like non bubble
is this another bub I just and me and
you have talked about before is like
they are vastly different markets and I
would say much more confident that this
is truly the fourth industrial
revolution today than maybe a year and a
half ago
>> as you've seen enterprise go down the go
down the route. So that's where I I just
think it's like but we're going to have
narratives and it's very easy for
investors to get caught up in narratives
and I think that's some of the danger
too in a market like this. The part that
I always find uh fascinating is as you
get that volatility, it will scare away
a lot of folks. But I actually think the
best investors, that's why they want to
play,
>> right? They want the volatility.
>> But but totally. But I think it's like
it's it's scary especially and me and
you obviously like big on social media
and we see it's like it's very easy to
get like scared into certain narratives
or what Nvidia does, you know, 8 hours
after they report a quarter. Is it
seeing? So, so I think it's one where
you have to follow the breadcrumbs. You
got to look at capbacks
what demand looks like in terms of you
know from the chip and the memory
players and obviously Nvidia and what
and like if you listen to other
conference calls I'm not just saying
tech I'm saying like just across the
board this there's no debate like this
is something where companies whether
it's financials healthcare you see it
yourself in terms of what you're
building the transformative nature of it
>> and I think it's one like and even when
it comes to physical AI In terms of the
future, will there be stocks that get
ahead of themselves near-term will there
be a lot of volatility? Of course,
you're going through probably the
biggest transformation we've seen in
over, you know, you could argue like a
hundred years, but I just think that's
exciting and you but you have to focus
on your northstar and I think that's the
important part.
>> All right. Where can we send people to
find more about Yorkville?
>> Yeah, so yorkvilles.com. you know, all
my stuff's on in terms of contacting me
and look, we're just so excited to just
be doing it. Such an exciting time.
>> And Dives Tech on uh X.
>> Yeah, Dives Tech X. Remember, I I only
blocked very very few people. And then
uh and actually I unblock I unblocked
some some people last week. And then uh
why did you unblock them?
>> Also on LinkedIn. Yeah. Just I felt
like, you know, maybe a change of tune
on this. You know, you you got you got
to give people a second chance.
>> Yeah. Why did they originally get
blocked? Look, I think you know
sometimes when I block people, it's just
like I understand like haters and
everything, but then you take it a step
too far.
>> It's like this. If you have a I have a
Shih Tzu and a Terry, a Shih Tzu, but
eventually if you keep pulling the tail
of a Shih Tzu, Shih Tzu is going to
bite, right? So, but then, you know, you
got to settle down. And I I I also I do
the rare uh unblock. Uh you know, as my
my good friend Mark Freeze says, the the
rare rare unblock.
>> All right. Well, hopefully uh to all the
haters who took it a step too far, they
were uh they were fortunate enough to
get the unblock. Do it again in the
future. Thank you.